<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Ridgway Musings - How To</title><link href="http://blog.aridgwayweb.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.aridgwayweb.com/feeds/how-to.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.aridgwayweb.com/</id><updated>2021-09-18T10:00:00+10:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>A New Way To Build A Free Blog</title><link href="http://blog.aridgwayweb.com/how-i-built-the-damn-thing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-18T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-09-18T10:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Ridgway</name></author><id>tag:blog.aridgwayweb.com,2021-09-18:/how-i-built-the-damn-thing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How I built this blog or doing stuff on the cheap!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently in conversation someone mentioned that github pages was a way to fire up a blog, set up a repo of a certain name under your user with the usual format (i.e an index.html) and &lt;em&gt;poof&lt;/em&gt; you now have a website capable of doing anything you need a website to do... free! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this is only to a point. A blog for example is simple a bunch of static pages with some JS, CSS and HTML easy peasy you're good to go. You want a full LAMP stack and complete server side control.. well... this solution is probably not for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I wanted to write in as my first post though was how I set this little corner of the web up. It was fun, quick, and REALLY easy to do and I thought I'd share how I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What You'll Need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this particular set up I am standing on the back of several technologies. 
1. &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;
2. &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; (no way out of this unfortunately)
3. &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; (I'm using 3.8 but I'm sure most 3+ version will work)
4. &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/bash/"&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt; (I build this on my linux laptop but WSL or MacOS should work more or less the same)
5. &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't go through how to install these as those links have much more thorough documentation I could ever provide. So from here on out I will assume you have configured and installed all the prereqs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...To Be Continued&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="How To"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="publishing"></category><category term="github pages"></category></entry></feed>